

Subhransu Maharana

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India Full Stack Engineer



+91 9886326216



subhransumaharana@gmail.com



https://subhnet.github.io



https://www.linkedin.com/in/smaharana



ABOUT ME

An Experienced Full-Stack Developer with 8 yrs of experience in designing, developing and implementing applications using range of technologies. Always keen to learn new technologies, Following best Quality Practices by applying Design Patterns, on-time Delivery.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Application Engineer

Jun 2019 - Present (3 years 4 months +)

Adobe

- Worked on building executive-focused Adobe analytics dashboards for Adobe's top digital marketing clients and developing custom web applications end to end to solve various customer needs.
- Developed and maintained a custom connector that syncs data between Microsoft D365 and Adobe Campaign. This connector allows users to sync contacts, custom entities between the two platforms with ease. Worked on building multiple modules, improving existing features and adding new ones.
- Automated the process of onboarding a client to Adobe Analytics, Launch, and Target for a Customer Website. This Framework has reduced the Consultant Efforts significantly by 90% and is now used across other teams.
- Developed serverless and event-driven applications based on events originating from various Adobe services using **Adobe I/O runtime**, events.
- Automated AEM CM deployment using Gulp Scripts, Github API, Github Actions, which enabled my teammates to significantly reduce the development effort.
- Deployed Big Data Pipelines in PySpark on AWS
- Migrated legacy Apache ETL process to WFE (Apache Airflow) for scaling and processing higher volumes of data
- Data Reprocessing for billions of records to cleanse the data in Adobe Analytics
- Mentored junior engineers in desgin and development of enterprise level solutions and help them gain industry knowledge and develop problem-solving skills
- Worked with tight deadlines and small consulting budgets to complete major tasks.

Server Side: Node.js, Express.js, Java, Docker, AWS-Lambda, EMR, EC2, GraphQL, Apache Openwhisk, Python, Pandas, pySpark, Kafka Client Side: ReactJS, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Software Engineer

Mar 2017 - May 2019 (2 years 3 months)

Fidelity Investments

- Responsible for upgrading the legacy codebase to Angular UI and Back-end in JAVA SpringBoot Restful Services. Develop testable, reusable, and maintainable components/services, integrating Restful APIs.
- Responsible for building a Table Component Framework for eTax Application, which made dynamic content to be easily customizable, focusing on its stability. It was reused across Multiple teams as well.
- Implemented Lazy-Loading, leading to an 85% reduction in web app loading time.
- Identified and suggested new technologies and tools for enhancing product value

Project Engineer

Sep 2014 - Feb 2017 (2 years 6 months)

Wipro Technologies

Bluedart Website Revamp

- Key Contributor in development and implementation of the project from build-out testing and integration into the production environment.
- Developing SOAP-based Web Services (bottom-up) which internally consumes various third-party vendors and also calls Oracle stored procs
- Google Map API Integration with shortest path implementation
- Technologies: LiferayAUI, JAVA, SOAP Webservices, axis2, Javascript, HTML, CSS



SKILLS

FRONT END

- ReactJS, AngularJS (4.4)
- HTML5, CSS
- Javascript(ES6)
- Typescript
- JQuery

BACK END

- Java
- Node.JS, ExpressJs
- Python, pandas framework
- Spring Framework
- SpringBoot
- MySQL
- Serverless Framework

DEVOPS

- AWS, Azure
- Docker
- Apache Openwhisk
- Apache Airflow
- Github Actions

MISCELLANEOUS SKILLS

GraphQL Gulp Git Tomcat NGINX Maven Webpack Babel Rest API, Adobe I/O



ACHIEVEMENTS

- "On the Spot Award" Awarded in Fidelity Investments, 2017.
- "Individual Award" Awarded for solving complex framework bugs in Fidelity, 2018.
- "Team of the Quarter" Awarded for contribution in Adobe, 2020
- Selected for "Adobe Tech Summit'21"
- Certified in "Azure Fundamentals -AZ-900"



EDUCATION

B.Tech, Computer Science Veer Surendra Sai University of Technology, Burla, Odisha 2010-2014